Blue Lagoon: The Awakening is a drama, adventure,
romance film directed by Jake Newsome.
Two high school students become stranded on a tropical
island and must rely on each other for survival.
They learn more about themselves and each other while falling in love.
Emmaline 'Emma' Robinson, played by Indiana Evans.
Dean McMullen, played by Brenton Thwaites.
Barbara Robinson, played by Denise Richards.
Jack McMullen, played by Patrick St. Esprit.
Phil Robinson, played by Frank John Hughes.
Lizzie, played by Alix Elizabeth Gitter.
Blue Lagoon: The Awakening is a 2012 American romantic drama
television film that premiered on Lifetime on June 16, 2012.
Indiana Evans and Brenton Thwaites star in the film, which is based on the
1908 novel The Blue Lagoon and its previous film adaptations.
It was a major departure from previous Blue Lagoon films in several respects.
The setting is contemporary, whereas the previous films were all set in the Victorian era; the lead characters were raised in normal society and are marooned as teenagers, rather than growing up on the island; the island the main characters
are stranded on is in the Caribbean, whereas the previous films took place in the Pacific Ocean; and roughly equal time is devoted to the uncivilized world of the island and the human society the characters were born into.
Christopher Atkins, the male lead in the 1980 film The
Blue Lagoon, also appears in the film.
The film explores themes of stranded, marooned, high school
student, deserted island, tropical island.
The tone is emotional.